SUMMARY

Voracious full-stack web developer who specializes in front-end aspects for 4 years and enthusiastic biomedical engineer with proven skills in ideation, creation, and leadership in 1 internship and several biomedical engineering projects. Interested in biomedical data integration and optimization in sports or eSports to enhance player performance and coaches' knowledge. Led front-end team to refactor company CSR website to increase customer engagement up to 800 users and completed 4 biomedical engineering projects: non-invasive glaucoma detection, wearable ECG, teenager fitness data acquisition, and non-invasive fetal electrocardiogram.

EDUCATION

Institut Teknologi Bandung Indonesia (2015-2019) - Bachelor of Engineering, majoring in Biomedical Engineering (GPA: 3.14)

ITB is one of the top universities in Indonesia in Natural Sciences and Engineering & Technology.

- Developed a full-stack website for managing hospital assets and warehouse for Ministry of Health of Malaysia Project
- Developed an electrode for wearable electrocardiogram vest and full stack website and cloud to manage, analyze and display ECG data
- Received Asrama Salman Scholarship 2016 and 2017
- Received YBP PLN Scholarship

EXPERIENCE

Suteki Tech (Education Technology Solutions Startup)

Bandung, Indonesia

Mar 2022 - Present

Front End Engineer

- Led front-end team for Company CSR Project, developing a website for college student management with data synchronization to The Ministry of Education, Culture, Research, and Technology Indonesia, serving 800+ university users.
- Created company source control documentation, optimizing processes for the main web product.
- Initiated migration from Vue 2 and Nuxt 2 to Vue 3 and Nuxt 3, enhancing performance and aligning with industry standards.
- Initiated development of the company 's private component library based on Vue 3 and Tailwind CSS.
- Conducted code reviews to improve overall code quality.
- Collaborated with backend, product owner, UI/UX, and quality assurance teams from grooming to UAT to ensure delivery of high-quality products.
- Initiated the refactoring of one of the company's products, migrating from JavaScript to TypeScript for improved maintainability and scalability.

E-Life Solution Plt Malaysia (startup consulting firm for technology solutions) **Front End Engineer Intern** Johor, Malaysia

May 2018 - Jul 2018

Received return offer at the end of internship

- Worked with a team of other developers on built hospital assets and inventory management systems
- Designed indoor positioning system for hospital assets utilizing Internet of Things
- Develop and build a front-end website to manage, analyze and display assets and inventory usage on the hospital

Databugar.itb.ac.id (Joint Project of three department in Institut Teknologi Bandung)

Bandung, Indonesia

Website Developer and Consultant

Feb 2019 – Jun 2022

As a web development project leader, planned, managed, and supervised the teenager fitness data Management web
development, coordinated with the design team, and presented to the client of 2 high school and entire first-year of the
university.

Bioelectricity Based Fetal Movement Detector (Freelance Project) **Research Engineer**

Bandung, Indonesia

July 2021 – Present

- Spearheaded the design and experimentation of biomedical instrumentation for bioelectricity-based fetal movement detectors, aiming for everyday use.
- Collaborated closely with midwives to develop mobile, user-friendly, and precise instrumentation for fetal movement detection.
- Utilized data analysis libraries such as SciPy and others, alongside Python and Google Colab, for comprehensive data analysis.

Robovis Laboratory (Biomedical Engineering Laboratory in Institut Teknologi Bandung) **Research Assistant**

Bandung, Indonesia Jun 2018 – Jun 2021

- Designed and experimented on biomedical instrumentation for everyday use and collaborated with doctors to develop mobile, user-friendly, precise instrumentation.
- Developed a non-invasive glaucoma detection to acquire and analyze EEG signal and detect glaucoma then display the
 result on a website.
- Developed a non-invasive fetal electrocardiogram to obtain fetal heart signal and analyze the outcome.

Regista (Sport GPS tracker and athlete management startup)

Bandung, Indonesia

Founder

Feb 2019 - Present

Designed and developed a sport GPS tracker for football players to track player vital and performance assessment tools.

Vent-I Ventilator Indonesia (COVID ventilator project by Masjid Salman ITB)

Bandung, Indonesia

Calibration Engineering Volunteer

Mar 2019 – Jun 2019

- Designed prototype calibrator for newly designed ventilator and High Flow Nasal Cannula (HFNC) for COVID 19.
- Conducted ventilator calibration and organized related documents to optimize HFNC production cost.

ORGANIZATIONAL ACTIVITIES

President - Pusat Teknologi Tepat Guna (Pustena)

Dec 2015 - Jul 2018

- Revitalize club and establish club foundation by collecting and implementing important document to plan and extends club life for 4 years
- Recruited 7 new members and designed new training curriculum to develop new member in technology aspects

Syiar Chief - Panitia Pelaksana Program Ramadhan (P3R) Salman ITB 1438 H

Dec 2016 - Jul 2017

• Led a team to plan and coordinate a Ramadhan Event with up to 20% member performance increase and client satisfaction.

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Certifications: Passed level C1 of CEFR by getting 7.5 overall band score on IELTS

Skills:

- Web Development: HTML, CSS, JS, ReactJS, VueJS, NuxtJS, NextJS, PostgreSQL, Nginx
- Data Processing: Python, TensorFlow, Google Suite
- Design: Adobe Photoshop, Krita, Manga Studio
- Language: English

Interests: Biomedical Engineering, Biomechanics, Web Development, Data Analysis in Sport and E-Sport